<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Hugo on Bart de Goede</title><link>https://bart.degoe.de/categories/hugo/</link><description>Recent content in Hugo on Bart de Goede</description><image><title>Bart de Goede</title><url>https://www.gravatar.com/avatar/af61db828941976309aaa8d7d76554fb</url><link>https://www.gravatar.com/avatar/af61db828941976309aaa8d7d76554fb</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.8</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 02:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bart.degoe.de/categories/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migrating my hopelessly outdated Hugo blog with Claude Code</title><link>https://bart.degoe.de/migrating-hugo-blog-with-claude-code/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 02:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://bart.degoe.de/migrating-hugo-blog-with-claude-code/</guid><description>I haven&amp;#39;t really touched my blog since 2019. The theme was ancient, jQuery was everywhere, and I kept putting off the inevitable migration. Then I decided to let an LLM do it. Here&amp;#39;s what happened when Claude Code spent an evening trying to modernize my setup.</description></item><item><title>Use Google Cloud Text-to-Speech to create an audio version of your blog posts</title><link>https://bart.degoe.de/use-google-cloud-text-to-speech-to-create-an-audio-version-of-your-blog-posts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://bart.degoe.de/use-google-cloud-text-to-speech-to-create-an-audio-version-of-your-blog-posts/</guid><description>Audio is big. Like really big, and growing fast, to the tune of &amp;#34;two-thirds of the population listens to online audio&amp;#34; and &amp;#34;weekly online listeners reporting an average nearly 17 hours of listening in the last week&amp;#34;. These numbers include all kinds of audio, from online radio stations, audiobooks, streaming services and podcasts (hi Spotify!). It makes sense too. Consuming audio content is easier to consume and more engaging than written content while you&amp;#39;re on the go, exercising, commuting or doing household chores. But what do you do if you&amp;#39;re like me and don&amp;#39;t have the time or recording equipment to ride this podcasting wave, and just write the occasional blog post?</description></item><item><title>Use Hugo Output Formats to generate Lunr index files for your static site search</title><link>https://bart.degoe.de/use-hugo-output-formats-to-generate-lunr-index-files/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 15:27:40 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://bart.degoe.de/use-hugo-output-formats-to-generate-lunr-index-files/</guid><description>I&amp;#39;ve been using Lunr.js to enable some basic site search on this blog. Lunr.js requires an index file that contains all the content you want to make available for search. In order to generate that file, I had a kind of hacky setup, depending on running a Grunt script on every deploy, which introduces a dependency on node, and nobody really wants any of that for just a static HTML website.</description></item><item><title>Free SSL on Github Pages with a custom domain: Part 2 - Let's Encrypt</title><link>https://bart.degoe.de/github-pages-and-lets-encrypt/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 22:34:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bart.degoe.de/github-pages-and-lets-encrypt/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages&lt;/a> has just become even more awesome. Since yesterday&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, GitHub Pages &lt;a href="https://blog.github.com/2018-05-01-github-pages-custom-domains-https/">supports HTTPS for custom domains&lt;/a>. And yes, it is still free!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Free SSL with a custom domain on GitHub Pages</title><link>https://bart.degoe.de/free-ssl-on-github-pages-with-a-custom-domain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 23:55:40 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bart.degoe.de/free-ssl-on-github-pages-with-a-custom-domain/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages&lt;/a> is pretty awesome. It lets you push a bunch of static HTML (and/or CSS and Javascript) to a GitHub repository, and they&amp;rsquo;ll host and serve it for you. For free!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Searching your Hugo site with Lunr</title><link>https://bart.degoe.de/searching-your-hugo-site-with-lunr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 23:38:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://bart.degoe.de/searching-your-hugo-site-with-lunr/</guid><description>&lt;p>Like many software engineers, I figured I needed a blog of sorts, because it would give me a place for my own notes on &amp;ldquo;How To Do Things™&amp;rdquo;, let me have a URL to give people, and share my ramblings about Life, the Universe and Everything Else with whoever wants to read them.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>